[inaudible] Welcome back. At this video, we're going to talk about how [inaudible]
[听不见]欢迎回来。在这段视频中，我们将谈论[听不见]
expressions are used to construct a full lexical specification on the programming
表达式用于构建关于编程的完整词法规范
language. Before we get started, I want to quickly summarize the notation for regular
语言。在我们开始之前，我想快速总结一下Regular的符号
expressions. One of the shorthand?s we talked about last time is a+ which means a
表情。我们上次谈到的速记之一是a+，意思是a
sequence of at least 1a or the language aa'lt;i>. Sometimes you'll see a vertical bar'lt;/i>
至少1a的序列或语言AA‘lt；i>。有时您会看到竖条；/i>
used instead of unions or a + b. Can also be written a vertical bar b and optional a
用来代替联合或a+b。也可以写成竖线b和可选的a
is abbreviation for the regular expression a + epsilon. And then we have character
是正则表达式a+epsilon的缩写。然后我们就有了性格
ranges which allows us to do a big union, a bunch of characters in order. And then
范围，这让我们可以做一个大的联合，一堆字符按顺序排列。然后
one more that's used, that's, that's actually fairly important but we didn't
还有一个用到了，就是，那其实是相当重要的，但是我们没有
discussed last time is the compliment of the character range. So this expression
上次讨论的是对人物范围的称赞。所以这个表达式
here means any character except the characters a through z. So the last
这里指的是除字符a到z之外的任何字符。
lecture, we talked about a specification for the following predicate. Given a
讲座中，我们讨论了以下谓词的规范。给出了一个
string s, is it in the language as the function l of a regular expression. As we,
字符串s，在语言中是不是正则表达式的函数l。当我们，
we define the language of regular expressions and talked about their
我们定义了正则表达式的语言，并讨论了它们的
semantics in terms of sets of strings. And so for any given regular expression, we
以字符串集表示的语义。因此，对于任何给定的正则表达式，我们
could reason out by hand whether a given string was in that language or not, and
可以手动推断给定的字符串是否使用该语言，并且
this turns out not to be enough for what we wanted to do. So just to review, what
事实证明，这对我们想要做的事情来说是不够的。所以，让我回顾一下，什么
is it we wanted to do when we're given an input, which is a bunch of characters, so
当我们得到一组字符的输入时，我们想要这样做吗，所以
here's a string of characters And it can be much longer than just setting
这里有一个字符串，它可以比仅仅设置
characters and. But we actually wanted to do is to partition the string. We want to
字符和。但我们实际上想要做的是对字符串进行分区。我们想要
drop lines in the strings, divide up into the words of language. Now of course each
在字符串中放入行，分成语言的单词。当然，现在每个人
one of these words are to be The language at some regular expression. But just
这些单词中的一个将作为某个正则表达式的语言。但只是
having a, a, a definition or a yes no answers, not quite the same thing as
具有一个、一个、一个定义或是否答案的，不完全等同于
having a method for partitioning a string into its constituting parts. And so we're
具有将字符串分割成其构成部分的方法的。所以我们要
gonna have to adapt regular expressions, to this problem and, and this requires
我必须调整正则表达式来解决这个问题，这需要
some small extensions and that's what this video is all about. So let's talk about
一些小的扩展，这就是这个视频的全部内容。所以我们来谈谈
how to do this. The first thing we're going to do, when we want to design the
如何做到这一点。我们要做的第一件事是，当我们想要设计
lexical specification of the language is we have to write the regular expression,
语言的词法规范就是我们要写正则表达式，
for the lexing to be to the [inaudible] classes and we, we talked about how to do
为了让词法兴去上[听不见的]课，我们讨论了如何做到这一点
this last time. So, for the numbers we might use digit plus desire as our regular
这是最后一次。因此，对于数字，我们可以使用数字加愿望作为我们的常量
expression and we might have a category of keywords which is just the list of all
表达式，我们可能有一个关键字类别，它只是所有关键字的列表
the, keywords in the language. We would have some category perhaps of identifiers.
语言中的关键字。我们可能会有某种类别的标识符。
There is the, definitely we talked about it last time. Sequences of letters or
那就是，我们上一次肯定谈到了。字母序列或
digits that begin with, with the letter and then we're having a bunch of. Bunch of
以字母开头的数字，然后我们有一串。一堆
punctuations, things like open parens, close parens, etc. So we write down a
标点符号，如左括号、右括号等。所以我们写下一个
whole set of regular expressions. One for each syntactic category in the language
一整套正则表达式。一个对应于语言中的每个句法类别
and that's the starting point for our lexical specification. The second step,
这就是我们词汇规范的起点。第二步，
what we're going to do is we're going to construct a gigantic regular expression
我们要做的是构建一个巨大的正则表达式
which just matches all the lexings for all the tokens and this is just the union, of
它正好匹配所有令牌的所有词条，这只是
all the regular expressions, that we wrote out on the previous slides. So we'll just
我们在前面的幻灯片中写出的所有正则表达式。所以我们就干脆
take the union of all those regular expressions and that forms, the lexical
以所有这些正则表达式和形式的并集为例，词法
specification of the language. And, we'll just write this out, we don't really care
语言的规范。我们就把这个写下来，我们真的不在乎
what these regular expressions are but they're just some, set r1, r2 and so on
这些正则表达式是什么，但它们只是一些，设置R1、R2等等
and the whole thing we're going to call r. And now, here's the heart of how we
我们将把整个东西命名为r。现在，这是我们如何
actually use this bicycle's specification to perform lexical analysis. So, let's
实际上是用这辆自行车的规格来进行词法分析。那么，让我们
consider an input. We input the string x1 up to xn. And now for every prefix of that
考虑一个输入。我们输入字符串x1到xn。现在，对于它的每个前缀
input, okay. We're going to check whether it's in the language of the regular
输入，好的。我们要检查一下它是不是用普通人的语言写的
expression. So we're gonna look at some prefix trying with the first character and
表达式。所以我们要看一些前缀尝试使用第一个字符
we're gonna ask ourselves is it in the language of that big regular expression.
我们会问自己，它是不是用那个大正则表达式的语言。
And if it is, if it is in the language, well then we know in particular that, that
如果是，如果是在语言中，那么我们特别知道，
prefix is in the language of one in the constituen t regular expressions cuz
前缀是构成正则表达式中的一的语言，因为
remember that r =. The sum of all the different talking classes of our language,
记住r=。我们语言的所有不同谈话课的总和，
okay. So we know that this prefix x1 through xi is in the language of sum rj.
好吧。所以我们知道这个前缀x1到xi是用和Rj的语言表示的。
Okay And so that we know that, that's a word. In our language is one of. Is in one
好的，我们知道了，这是一个词。在我们的语言中是其中之一。是合而为一的
of the talking classes that we're interested in, And so what we do is we
我们感兴趣的谈话课程，所以我们所做的就是
simply delete that prefix from the input and then we go back to three and we
只需从输入中删除前缀，然后我们返回到3，然后我们
repeat. And in this way we keep biting off prefixes of the input and we'll do this
重复一遍。通过这种方式，我们不断地咬掉输入的前缀，然后我们就可以这样做了
until the string is empty and then we have [inaudible] analyzed the entire program.
直到字符串为空，然后我们分析了整个程序(听不见)。
Now this algorithm has a couple of ambiguities or a couple of things that are
现在这个算法有几个模棱两可的地方，或者说有几件事是
under specified and those are actually interesting. So let's take a moment and
在指定的范围内，而这些实际上是很有趣的。所以让我们花点时间
talk about those. The first question is how much input is actually used? So, let's
说说这些吧。第一个问题是实际使用了多少输入？那么，让我们
consider the following situation. Let's say that, we have, the x1 to xi, is in the
请考虑以下情况。比方说，我们有x1到xi，在
language of our lexical specification. And let's say there's a different prefix,
我们的词汇规范的语言。假设有一个不同的前缀，
that's also in the language of our lexical specification and of course your I is, is
这也是我们的词汇规范中的语言，当然你的i is，is
not equal to J. What does that look like? Well, it would look like the following
不等于J。那看起来像什么？嗯，它看起来如下所示
kind of situation; we would have our input string. And we have two different prefixes
一种情况；我们将拥有我们的输入字符串。我们有两个不同的前缀
of the input that are both valid talking classes and the question is which one of
这两个输入都是有效的谈话类，问题是哪一个是
these do we want? And, you know just be kind of [inaudible] here to have a
这些是我们想要的吗？而且，你知道，在这里有一种[听不见]的
concrete example, let's consider. What happens when a =,,,, = is at the, is at
具体的例子，让我们来考虑一下。当a=，=在、在时会发生什么情况
the beginning of the input. After we chopped off a bunch of other input and
输入的开始。在我们切断了一堆其他输入之后
perhaps we have this sub-string or this prefix of the input that we're looking at
也许我们有我们正在查看的输入的这个子字符串或前缀
and the question is, you know should this be regarded as a single = which would be
问题是，你知道，这是否应该被认为是一个单一的=，这将是
an assignment operator in most languages or would it be regards to =,,,, = which in
大多数语言中的赋值运算符，或者是否将其视为=、=，其中
some language is a comparison operator? And, and this is an example we've looked
有些语言是比较运算符吗？这是我们看过的一个例子
at before and discussed, and there's actually a well defined answer to this
并进行了讨论，实际上对此有一个明确的答案
question. And, it is, that we should always take the longer one and this has a
问题来了。它是，我们应该总是花更长的时间，这有一个
name that's c alled the maximal munch. So the rule is that when faced with a choice
名字叫“最大的咀嚼”。所以规则是，当面临选择的时候
of two different prefixes of the input, either which would be a valid token, we
输入的两个不同前缀(这两个前缀都可能是有效的令牌)，我们
should always choose the longer one. And, the reason for this is that's just the way
应该总是选择较长的那个。这样做的原因就是这就是
humans themselves read things so when we see =,,,, = we don't see two different
人类自己读东西，所以当我们看到=，=时，我们看不到两个不同的东西
equal operators, we see =,,,, = and if I. Look at, you know that the sentence that I
相等运算符，我们看到=，如果是I。看，你知道这句话，I
wrote up here, you know when we look at HOW, we don't see three letters. We gather
写在这里，你知道，当我们看的时候，我们看不到三个字母。我们聚集在一起
that altogether in one long token. We go as far as we can until we see a separator
总而言之，这是一个很长的令牌。我们尽我们所能，直到看到分隔符
and so because this is the way humans work; we make the tools work the same way
因为这是人类的工作方式，所以我们让工具以同样的方式工作
and this normally or almost always does the right thing. Second question is which
这通常或几乎总是做正确的事。第二个问题是
token should be used if more than one token matches? So what do I mean by that?
如果有多个令牌匹配，是否应该使用令牌？我这么说是什么意思？
Well, again we have our prefix of the input and it's in the language of our
好的，我们同样有我们的输入前缀，它是用我们的语言编写的
lexical specification and just remember that the lexical specification itself
词汇规范，只需记住词汇规范本身
again is made up as the union, a bunch of regular expressions for token classes.
同样由联合组成，这是一组用于令牌类的正则表达式。
Now, since that, since this prefix, is in the language of the lexical, lexical
现在，既然这个前缀是在词汇的语言中，
specification, that means that it again, it must be in the language of some
规范，也就是说，它一定是用某种语言
particular token class, rj. But nothing says that it isn't also in the language of
特定令牌类，RJ。但没有人说它不也是用
a completely different token class. Meaning, at the same string could be
一个完全不同的令牌类。也就是说，在同一字符串中可能是
interpreted as a, as one of two different tokens and the question is if this
被解释为两个不同令牌中的一个，问题是如果这
happens, which one should we pick? So, for example just to make this concrete, Recall
发生了，我们该选哪一个呢？所以，举个例子，为了让这件事具体化，回想一下
that we could have a lexical specification for key words which would be things like
我们可以对关键字有一个词汇规范，比如
if and else, and so on, and also for identifiers. And then the identifier was
IF和ELSE等等，还有标识符。然后标识符是
the letter Followed by a letter or a digit. Repeat it, okay. And if you look at
字母后跟字母或数字。重复一遍，好吗。如果你看一下
these two specifications, you'll see that the string if, IF is both of them. So IF
这两个规范，您会看到字符串if，if都是它们。所以如果
is in the language of keywords, And it's also in the language of the identifiers.
是关键字的语言，也是标识符的语言。
And so should we treat it as a keyword or an identifier. Now the normal rule in most
因此，我们应该将其视为关键字还是标识符。现在大多数人的正常规则是
languages is that if it's a keyword then i t's always a keyword and you know the
语言是，如果它是一个关键字，那么它总是一个关键字，你知道
identifier is actually don't include the keywords. And but actually it's a real
标识符实际上是不包括关键字的。但实际上这是一个真正的
pain to write out the identifiers in such a way that you explicitly exclude the key
以显式排除键的方式写出标识符是一件很痛苦的事
words. This is a much more natural definition I've written here for the
单词。这是我在这里为
identifiers. And so the way this gets resolved is by a priority ordering and
标识符。所以解决这个问题的方式是通过优先顺序和
typically the rule is to choose the one Listed first. Okay. So when there is a
通常情况下，规则是先选择列出的那个。好吧。所以当有一个
choice, when there is more than one token class which the string might be long, the
选项，当有多个字符串可能很长的令牌类时，
one that is listed first is given higher priority. So in our file defining our
最先列出的优先级较高。所以在我们的文件中定义了我们的
lexical specification we would put the key words before the identifiers just as we
词法规范我们会将关键字放在标识符之前，就像我们
have done here. The final question is what to do if no rule matches. What if I have
在这里都做了些什么。最后一个问题是，如果没有匹配的规则，该怎么办。如果我有呢？
the prefix of the input? That is not in the language Of my lexical specification.
输入的前缀是什么？这不在我的词汇规范中的语言中。
Now this can actually arise. Certainly there are lots and lots of strings that
现在，这实际上可能会出现。当然有很多很多的弦
are not gonna be in the language of the lexical specification of most languages.
不会出现在大多数语言的词汇规范中。
And the question is how to handle that situation? So it's very important for
问题是如何处理这种情况？所以这对我们来说非常重要
compilers to do good error handling. They can't simply crash. They need to be able
编译器做好错误处理。它们不能简单地坠毁。他们需要能够
to give the user, the programmer a feedback about where the error is and what
为了向用户提供关于错误位置和错误内容的反馈
kind of error it is so we do need to handle this gracefully. And the best
这是一种错误，所以我们确实需要优雅地处理这个问题。也是最好的
solution for lexical analysis is to not do this so don't let this ever happen. And so
词法分析的解决方案是不这样做，所以不要让这种情况发生。因此，
what we wanted to do instead is to write a category of error strings, So, all of the
相反，我们想要做的是编写一类错误字符串，因此，所有
strings. Not in the lexical specification of the language. So we write out a regular
弦。不在该语言的词汇规范中。所以我们写了一份定期报告
expression. Again this is another regular expression here. For all the possible
表达式。同样，这也是另一个正则表达式。尽一切可能
error strings, all the possible erroneous strings that could occur as you know
错误字符串，如您所知，所有可能出现的错误字符串
invalid lexical input and then we put it last. Put it last in priority. So that it
无效的词汇输入，然后我们将其放在最后。把它放在最后。这样它就可以
will match after everything else matches and, and the reason for putting it last.
会在其他一切都匹配之后再匹配，以及把它放在最后的原因。
Is that, this actually allows us to be a little bit sloppy in, in how we define the
那就是，这实际上允许我们在如何定义
error strings. It can actually overlap, with earlier regular expressi ons. We can
错误字符串。它实际上可以与早期的常规表达式重叠。我们可以的
include things in the error strings that are in fact not errors. But, if we put it
在错误字符串中包含实际上不是错误的内容。但是，如果我们把它
last in priority, then it will only match if no earlier regular expression match and
优先级最后，则仅当没有更早的正则表达式匹配时，它才会匹配，并且
so in fact, they will only catch the error strings. Then the action that we'll take
因此，实际上，它们只会捕获错误字符串。然后我们将采取的行动
when we match the error string will be the prints in the error message and give
当我们匹配错误字符串时，将在错误消息中打印并给出
device a feedback like where it is in the file and such. To wrap up this video,
设备提供反馈，如它在文件中的位置等等。为了结束这段视频，
regular expressions are very nice and concise notation for string patterns but
正则表达式是字符串模式的非常好和简明的表示法，但是
to use them in lexical analysis requires a couple of small extensions. Some
要在词法分析中使用它们，需要几个小扩展。一些
particulars, a couple of ambiguities we have to resolve, we want our matches to be
细节，我们必须解决的几个模棱两可的问题，我们希望我们的匹配是
as long as possible. So we take. As much input at a time as we can and we also want
越久越好。所以我们就拿走了。一次尽可能多地投入，我们还希望
to choose the highest Priority match. So, the regular expressions are given a
若要选择最高优先级的匹配，请执行以下操作。因此，正则表达式被赋予一个
priority. The different token classes have priorities and, when there's tie, when the
优先权。不同的令牌类具有优先级，并且当存在平局时，
same, prefix of the input could match more than one, we pick the one that has the
相同，输入的前缀可以匹配多个，我们选择具有
highest priority. Typically this has done just by listing them in order in a file
最高优先级。通常，只需在文件中按顺序列出它们就可以做到这一点
and the ones listed first have higher priority over the ones listed later. I
而且排在第一位的优先于排在后面的优先级。我
just wanna warn you that when you go to right lexical specifications, when you go
我只想提醒你，当你进入正确的词汇规范，当你
to actually implement, lexor for a language, the interaction of these two
要真正实现一种语言的词法分析器，这两者的交互
rules that we take longest possible matches and we break ties and favor of the
我们尽可能长时间比赛的规则，我们打破平局，偏爱
highest priority rules. That this lead to some tricky situations and it's not always
最高优先级规则。这会导致一些棘手的情况，而且并不总是
obvious that you're getting exactly what you want, You have to think carefully
显然你得到的正是你想要的，你必须仔细考虑
about the Ordering of the rules and it's actually how you write the rules so that
关于规则的顺序，它实际上是如何写规则的，所以
you get the behavior that you desire. And finally to handle errors, we typically
你会得到你想要的行为。最后，为了处理错误，我们通常
write out. Catch all regular expression that soaks up all the possible erroneous
写出来。捕获吸收所有可能的错误的所有正则表达式
strings and give it the lowest priority so that it only triggers if no valid token
字符串，并为其赋予最低优先级，以便只有在没有有效令牌时才会触发
class matches some piece of the input. If I leave, we haven't discussed these yet
类与输入的某些部分匹配。如果我走了，我们还没有讨论过这些
but they are very good algorithm to know for implementing all of these and in fact
但它们是实现所有这些的非常好的算法，而且实际上
we'll be able to do it in only single pass over the input and with very few
我们只需通过一次输入即可完成此操作，而且使用的资源很少
operations per character. Just a few, Just a simple table look up and this would be
每个字符的操作数。只有几个，只要简单地查一下桌子，这就是
the subject of our future videos.
我们未来视频的主题。